Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 57.
We are asked to add a node at the front of the list.
So in the previous video, we have created a class called node.
It contains few pointers that previous and next and contains data that it is of type and OK, and we
have created an object of its type called ahead.
Now we are going to create a method that allow pushing and adding a node at the front of the list.
OK.
What I mean, adding at the front of the list?
It means at the beginning of the list.
OK, so beginning of the list and we have learned about this in the lecture.
So please go back and forth the previous previous lectures and see how to add the what is the algorithm
of adding nodes at the beginning of the list?
And then we are going to apply this directly by codes in Java.
So let's start.
First of all.
First step, we start by making the units making one making.
And you note, so node new nodes equal to new nodes and took into meter the new date.
So how to create how to get the new date in order to create a node?
I need the data in order to create its own date.
So for that, I need to pass into the perimeter of this method.
The end new date?
OK.
I passed into their perimeter new data, and then I will create a new node that contains this date.
Now, the second step is making the next.
Often you node as the head and the previous.
As not.
OK, so linking linkage, this is the big step I prefer, like naming it as linking or linkage.
So we have created the data of the node.
Now I will create the next and the previous of the node.
So new node
next equal.
What is the next?
When you put anything in the front of the list or at the beginning of the list, it would be the head
of the previous before add the addition.
So consider that you have three nodes.
The head of the first no, the had of this list is the first node.
So if I need to insert a node before the first one, I should refer the next to this.
Had that, that is currently being that start of the list now new node here that the previous equal
to now because there is nothing that there's previous of the first node in a double endangered list,
and we are making this method in order to allow the user to insert a node at the beginning of the list.
So before this newly created node, there is nothing.
So its reference would be not.
It's very simple.
Now let's move to the third method.
Or state?
If we need to change the previous pre preview of our previous of had no to new note, so we need to
make it conditional stay, so change previous of had no to New York.
This is the trick behind additions.
We need to check if have does not equal to no.
Then had that the previous pirates, but it had that previous equal to new note.
OK?
This is very simple.
And the fourth estate or first step move that had to point to that and, you know, it had equal to,
you know.
OK, so now head, which is here, which is the object that we have created as global head equal to,
then, you know?
OK.
It's very simple.
Now let's create the main method to test it.
Testing public static
void main.
By the way, you can get free coupons.
Do you enroll in our The Complete Java Developer course?
OK.
So in order to Master Chef to become professional and Java developed system that allowed the print and
I will put here adding new date, new notes
I will push.
So I will put here I will make it public static in order to allow with its access.
Bush.
I need.
What is there?
You know it.
Aesthetic, so make no static, OK, public, less static, less known.
OK.
And had.
I will make it this high risk.
I will make undo.
For making it a static, so.
I will do it now, I can access this by putting doubling at least the bush.
No, you can make it by this bush by making an instance of double link at last the an equal to new Dublin
and could last.
And I start by calling the elder bush.
I need to push here the newly created data I will push number one.
OK, so the first note inside this deal would be equal to one.
In the next video, we are going to write a method that prints all components of this doubly linked
list, and we will see how this works.
OK.